<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<help>
	<title>Help page</title>
	<content>
		<h3>Help</h3>
		<p>The content of this page is help for using Geonetwork. It is not intended as a help guide for editors or administrators. That can be found xxx.</p>
		<br/>
		<h3>Content of this page:</h3>
		<p>
			<a href="#1">Finding data</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#2">Simple search</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#3">Advanced search</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#4">Data themes</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#5">Recently updated</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#6">How to add metadata</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#7">Sharing metadata records</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#8">Exporting records</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#9">Emailing the metadata link</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#10">Permanent link to the record</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#11">Deleting records</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#12">Defenitions</a>
			<br/>
			<a href="#13">Show map</a>
		</p>
		<br/>
		<h3>Content sections:</h3>
		<a name="1"/>
		<h1>Finding spatial data</h1>
		<p>
			<i>Metadata Catalogue</i> offers a simple and advanced search.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="2"/>
		<h1>Simple search</h1>
		<p>The simple search allows you to search on the following fields:
			<ul>
				<li>Title</li>
				<li>Abstract</li>
				<li>Keywords</li>
				<li>Location</li>
				<li>Free text (any metadata field)</li>
			</ul>	
		Note - Keywords are not case sensitive.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="3"/>
		<h1>Advanced search</h1>
		<p>What can you do here? How much detail do we want to go into?.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="4"/>
		<h1>Data themes</h1>
		<p>The data themes section shows all records within an environmental theme. Every record sits in the most relevant theme. Records may sit under more than one theme.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="5"/>
		<h1>Recently updated</h1>
		<p>The recently updated section shows the 10 most recently updated records. This could be a change to one field or to many.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="6"/>
		<h1>How to add metadata</h1>
		<p>If you want to add a record to name of solution please email metadata@environment-agency.gov.uk
		When we know who our editors are we can list them here and expand this section.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="7"/>
		<h1>Sharing metadata records</h1>
		<p>Records can be saved and exported and links emailed and book-marked.<br/>
		Note – these records contain personal information. Please do not share externally.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="8"/>
		<h1>Exporting records</h1>
		<p>This functionality is for when you want to share or re-use a metadata record with others.

		This can be done in numerous ways:
		<ul>
				<li>Save the file as ISO 19139 xml</li>
				<li>Save the file as DublinCore xml</li>
				<li>Save the record as a pdf</li>
			</ul>
		These can be done as individual records or by selecting many.<br/>
		Select the record(s) you want to save and in ‘actions on selection’ choose one of the options.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="9"/>
		<h1>Emailing the metadata link</h1>
		<p>Viewing a record – envelope icon on top left of record.
		This functionality allows you to send an email with the metadata records unique ID.
		Need more info as what the purpose of this is.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="10"/>
		<h1>Permanent link to the record</h1>
		<p>Star icon on top left of record
		This shows the metadata records full URL which includes the unique ID.
		Need more info as what the purpose of this is.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="11"/>
		<h1>Deleting records</h1>
		<p>Metadata records cannot be deleted. We keep all records for historic purposes.
		There is the functionality for administrators to retire records but these would need good reason - define what this is or link to process/guidance.</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="12"/>
		<h1>Definitions</h1>
		<p>
			Definitions of dataset, data series, data services, spatial and published. These are all terms within our metadata.<br/>
			<ul><li>
					<em>Dataset</em> - A dataset is a defined collection of digital data, typically a list or table of facts, which is held, extracted or formatted for a specific business purpose.</li>
				<li>
					<em>Data Series</em> - Data Collection of datasets sharing the same product specification</li>
				<li>
					<em>Data Services </em> - An interface that allows the delivery of the data via the Internet be it either a view, feature or invoke service.</li>
				<li>
					<em>Spatial</em> - A dataset that is spatially referenced and stored as a GIS or Geomatic file format such as .shp, .tab, WMS, ASCII etc.</li>
				<li>
					<em>Published</em> - A dataset that has been proactively disseminated and is available via a recognised Data Sharing Platform service and discoverable by metadata.</li>
			</ul>
		</p>
		<br/>
		<a name="13"/>
		<h1>Show map</h1>
		<p>This functionality isn’t fully enabled in this version and we recommend that you do not use it<br/>
		</p>
	</content>
</help>
